Interviewer: Do you have any phobias?
Jo: Yes, I’m very scared of spiders.
Interviewer: And how long have you had this phobia?
Jo: I’ve had it since I was a child, so for more than 40 years.
Interviewer: Did something happen to start the phobia?
Jo: Um well, not really, I’ve always been a bit afraid of spiders,
maybe because my sisters used to chase me with them when I was a child,
and I think as I got older, my fear got worse.
But then something happened when I was in my 20s that made me think I had a real problem.
I was in the car with my boyfriend, he was driving, and the road was very busy,
and suddenly I saw a huge spider on the floor of the car, next to my foot.
I was terrified, and my instinct was to try to get away from the spider as quickly as possible,
so I opened my door, while he was still driving.
It was really dangerous.
Luckily he managed to stop and nothing happened,
but I knew then that I had to do something about my phobia,
have some therapy, you know, get some professional help.
Interviewer: What kind of therapy did you have?
How long did it take?
Jo: I did a ‘spider phobia’ course, it was a one-day course at London Zoo.
Eh, we were a group of about 15 people.
First there was a session with a doctor.
We learned a lot of facts about spiders, and talked about what we were afraid of,
and we did a hypnotherapy session.
Then we went to the spider house.
The other people on the course went up close to the glass to look at the spiders,
and they were saying, ‘Ah I’m cured, I feel fine’.
But I stayed at the back of the group, and I was crying because I was still terrified.
But a bit later I was able to pick up a small spider with a piece of paper
and a glass over the top of it and walk across the room.
And by the end of the day, I could hold a tarantula, which was amazing.
Interviewer: Do you still have the phobia now?
Jo: Well, yes I do, but now if I see one, I am more logical about it,
my first reaction is to be frightened, but then with a little bit of talking to myself,
and if it’s not too big, I can usually deal with it.